hey guys this looks like a fun one it's
a no calculator challenge it's 3 x = 69
and 23 to the Y = 69 and it wants to
know what is 1x + 1 over y if you want
to try it on your own pause it right now
because I'm going to solve it in 3 2 one
first let's copy these down and let's
put everything in parentheses for the
first equation let's exponentiate both
sides to 1 /x power and on the bottom
one let's exponentiate both sides to the
1/ Y power let's go back to the top one
these two exponents are going to
multiply by each other so x * 1X is XX
and X overx is equal to 1 so this is 3
to the 1 or in other words three and
bottom same thing these two exponents
are going to multiply so y * 1 over Y is
y over Y and that's equal to 1 and 23 to
the 1 is 23 so what I like about this is
we now have a 1 /x right here and a one
over y right here we just got to figure
out some way to add these together we
could use logarithms but I want to try
something else let's take this bottom
equation and multiply both sides by
three and since we know 3 is equal to 69
1 /x in the place of this three let's
plug in 69 1 /x on the left hand side 3
* 23 is equal to 69 and on the right
hand side these two have the same base
so we can use these notes right here
anytime two powers are being multiplied
with the same base you can just add the
exponents so these both have a base of
69 so we can just add these two
exponents it'll be 1 y + 1X and on the
left hand side let's give this 69 an
exponent it' be 69 to the 1 now from
here since they both have a base of 69
the only way these two equations can be
equal to each other is if the exponents
are equal to each other so we can set 1
equal to 1 y + 1 /x and now we're
basically done we can rearrange them
like this and we can put a box around it
now we can move it up here in this
challenge 1x + 1 Y is equal to 1 how
exciting